const HistoryQuestions = [
    {
        question: "Who was the first caliph of Islam?",
        options: ["Uthman ibn Affan", "Ali ibn Abi Talib", "Abu Bakr al-Siddiq", "Umar ibn al-Khattab"],
        correct_option: "Abu Bakr al-Siddiq"
    },
    {
        question: "In which year did the Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) make the Hijra (migration) to Medina?",
        options: ["632 CE", "610 CE", "630 CE", "622 CE"],
        correct_option: "622 CE"
    },
    {
        question: "What was the first battle fought in Islam?",
        options: ["Conquest of Mecca", "Battle of Khandaq", "Battle of Uhud", "Battle of Badr"],
        correct_option: "Battle of Badr"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first female martyr in Islam?",
        options: ["Khadijah bint Khuwaylid", "Fatimah bint Muhammad", "Aisha bint Abu Bakr", "Sumayyah bint Khayyat"],
        correct_option: "Sumayyah bint Khayyat"
    },
    {
        question: "Which caliphate period is known as the 'Golden Age' of Islam?",
        options: ["Fatimid Caliphate", "Rashidun Caliphate", "Abbasid Caliphate", "Umayyad Caliphate"],
        correct_option: "Abbasid Caliphate"
    },
    {
        question: "Who founded the city of Baghdad in 762 CE?",
        options: ["Al-Mu'tasim", "Al-Mamun", "Harun al-Rashid", "Al-Mansur"],
        correct_option: "Al-Mansur"
    },
    {
        question: "Which Islamic scholar is known as the 'Father of Algebra'?",
        options: ["Al-Farabi", "Ibn Sina", "Al-Kindi", "Al-Khwarizmi"],
        correct_option: "Al-Khwarizmi"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first Muslim woman to lead an army in battle?",
        options: ["Zainab bint Muhammad", "Fatimah bint Muhammad", "Aisha bint Abu Bakr", "Khawlah bint al-Azwar"],
        correct_option: "Khawlah bint al-Azwar"
    },
    {
        question: "Which famous Islamic scholar wrote the book 'Al-Muwatta'?",
        options: ["Imam Bukhari", "Imam Muslim", "Imam Abu Hanifa", "Imam Malik"],
        correct_option: "Imam Malik"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the last caliph of the Ottoman Caliphate?",
        options: ["Sultan Selim I", "Abdul Hamid II", "Mehmed VI", "Abdulmejid II"],
        correct_option: "Abdulmejid II"
    }
];

export default HistoryQuestions;
